JING QUAN BUNG



Web API Engineer / DevOps Engineer / IoT System Integrator / Solution Architect

DETAILS

EMAIL

jqbung0318@gmail.com

SOCIAL LINKS

statusunknownthings.com github.com/jqbung0318 linkedin.com/in/jqbung-techies/

LANGUAGES

- Chinese*
- English*
- Bahasa Malaysia
- Cantonese

EDUCATION

BSc Hons Software Engineering, University of Nottingham, Malaysia.

ACHIEVEMENTS

 AWS Certified Solution Architect – Associate

SKILLS

Cloud Service Platform

 AWS, GCP, Azure, Alibaba Cloud

Programming Language

 Python Django, NodeJS, GoLang, C Arduino

DevOps Tools

- Terraform, Jenkins, Ansible, Docker, Kubernetes
- Proxmox, TrueNAS, pfSense SVN
- GitHub, JIRA, Trello, Linear

PROFILE

NodeJS/Python Web Backend Developer with 4 years of experience in building micro-services and real-time system. Professionally utilising Amazon Web Services to design and deploy software solutions for productions. Strive for software solution architect role to assist in designing complex, flexible, multi-levelled system to enhance developing experience and end-user experience.

EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

Web Backend Engineer, Xamble Technologies Sdn Bhd

Kuala Lumpur 2022 – 2023

- DevOps developer and maintainer for car listing websites for well-known local newspaper publisher.
- Successfully designed a core backend architecture on top of AWS and practice it among the developers in the team.
- Web backend developer for social marketing creator application with pay-out, chat & community integrations. Responsible for architecture design and DevOps tasks.

Software Architect, Pixel Pine Sdn Bhd

Kuala Lumpur 2019 –2022

- Collaborate with the CEO, CTO, and Product Lead to analyse the business requirements ranging from in-house fleet management to external warehouse management projects.
- Highly involved in designing development tools for serverless based application on AWS. Successfully reduce up to 50% of time in blue-green deployment with proper unit testing.
- Productive and positive project team lead to guide team members to design, develop, and deploy IoT solutions ranges from agriculture, logistics, contact tracing, and individual tracking.

Part Time Full Stack Developer, Pixel Pine Sdn Bhd

Kuala Lumpur 2017 – 2018

- Deployed a single authentication system to access server monitoring and customer support ticketing services using open source software
- Built a micro-service to generate daily, customizable SLA reports on ticketing service